ideas-r-us-software.uk 2018-06-29

# Ideas R Us Software - Privacy Policy

##  Privacy Policy

### 1\. Introduction

1.1 We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website visitors; in this policy we explain how we will treat your personal information.

1.2 By using our website and agreeing to this policy, you consent to our use of cookies in accordance with the terms of this policy.

### 2\. Credit

2.1 This document was created using a template from SEQ Legal ([http://www.seqlegal.com](http://www.seqlegal.com/)).

### 3\. Collecting personal information

3.1 We may collect, store and use the following kinds of personal information:

(a) information about your computer and about your visits to and use of this website including your IP address.

(b) information that you provide to us when registering with our website (including your email address).

(e) information that you provide to us when using the services on our website, or that is generated in the course of the use of those services (including the timing, frequency and pattern of service use).

(f) information relating to any purchases you make of our goods and/or services or any other transactions that you enter into through our website (including your name, address, telephone number, and email address).

(g) information that you post to our website for publication on the internet including your user name, your profile pictures and the content of your posts.

(h) information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us or send through our website (including the communication content and metadata associated with the communication).

3.2 Before you disclose to us the personal information of another person, you must obtain that person's consent to both the disclosure and the processing of that personal information in accordance with this policy.

### 4\. Using personal information

4.1 Personal information submitted to us through our website will be used for the purposes specified in this policy or on the relevant pages of the website.

4.2 We may use your personal information to:

(a) administer our website and business.

(c) enable your use of the services available on our website.

(e) supply to you services purchased through our website.

(f) send statements, invoices and payment reminders to you, and collect payments from you.

(g) send you non-marketing commercial communications.

(h) send you email notifications that you have specifically requested.

(l) deal with enquiries and complaints made by or about you relating to our website.

(m) keep our website secure and prevent fraud.

(n) verify compliance with the terms and conditions governing the use of our website (including monitoring private messages sent through our website private messaging service).

4.3 If you submit personal information for publication on our website, we will publish and otherwise use that information in accordance with the licence you grant to us.

4.5 We will not, without your express consent, supply your personal information to any third party for the purpose of their or any other third party's direct marketing.

4.6 All our website financial transactions are handled through our payment services provider, PayPal. You can review the provider's privacy policy at <https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full>. We will share information with our payment services provider only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing payments you make via our website, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds.

### 5\. Disclosing personal information

5.3 We may disclose your personal information: 

(a) to the extent that we are required to do so by law;

(b) in connection with any ongoing or prospective legal proceedings;

(c) in order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights (including providing information to others for the purposes of fraud prevention and reducing credit risk);

5.4 Except as provided in this policy, we will not provide your personal information to third parties.

### 6\. International data transfers

6.1 Information that we collect may be stored and processed in and transferred between any of the countries in which we operate in order to enable us to use the information in accordance with this policy.

6.3 Personal information that you publish on our website or submit for publication on our website may be available, via the internet, around the world. We cannot prevent the use or misuse of such information by others.

6.4 You expressly agree to the transfers of personal information described in this Section 6.

### 7\. Retaining personal information

7.1 This Section 7 sets out our data retention policies and procedure, which are designed to help ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of personal information.

7.2 Personal information that we process for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes.

7.4 Notwithstanding the other provisions of this Section 7, we will retain documents (including electronic documents) containing personal data:

(a) to the extent that we are required to do so by law;

(b) if we believe that the documents may be relevant to any ongoing or prospective legal proceedings; and

(c) in order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights (including providing information to others for the purposes of fraud prevention and reducing credit risk).

### 8\. Security of personal information

8.1 We will take reasonable technical and organisational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information.

8.2 We will store all the personal information you provide on our secure (password- and firewall-protected) servers.

8.3 All electronic financial transactions entered into through our website will be protected by encryption technology.

8.4 You acknowledge that the transmission of information over the internet is inherently insecure, and we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the internet.

8.5 You are responsible for keeping the password you use for accessing our website confidential; we will not ask you for your password (except when you log in to our website).

### 9\. Amendments

9.1 We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website.

9.2 You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy.

9.3 We may notify you of changes to this policy by email or through the private messaging system on our website.

### 10\. Your rights

10.1 You may instruct us to provide you with any personal information we hold about you; provision of such information will be subject to:

(a) the payment of a fee (currently fixed at GBP 10); and

(b) the supply of appropriate evidence of your identity (for this purpose, we will usually accept a photocopy of your passport certified by a solicitor or bank plus an original copy of a utility bill showing your current address).

10.2 We may withhold personal information that you request to the extent permitted by law.

10.3 You may instruct us at any time not to process your personal information for marketing purposes.

10.4 In practice, you will usually either expressly agree in advance to our use of your personal information for marketing purposes, or we will provide you with an opportunity to opt out of the use of your personal information for marketing purposes.

### 11\. Third party websites

11.1 There are no links to third party websites (except user created content).

### 12\. Updating information

12.1 Please let us know if the personal information that we hold about you needs to be corrected or updated.

### 13\. Cookies

13.1 See our Cookies Policy Cookies.

### 14\. Data protection registration

14.1 We are registered as a data controller with the UK Information Commissioner's Office.

14.2 Our data protection registration number is ZA192618.

### 15\. Our details

15.1 This website is owned and operated by Ian Wadsworth.

15.3 Our principal place of business is at Brighouse, West Yorkshire, England.

15.4 You can contact us by using our website contact form, or by email to [contact@ideas-r-us.co.uk](mailto:contact@ideas-r-us.co.uk).
